Guide to the Samuel Stark Theatre collection addenda, 1868-1990
Department of Special Collections
Samuel Stark Theatre collection addenda,
1868-1990
Special Collections M0593
Stark, Samuel.
5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Bequest of Samuel Stark, 1991.
Biographical Note
Authority on history of the theatre, particularly American theatre, and collector of theatre material, including photos, autographs, clippings, etc. Particular interest in Cole Porter.
Scope and Content
Correspondence and subject files, scrapbooks, vocal scores, Stark index addenda, photographs, autograph collections, etc. Much of the material deals with Cole Porter, including a video tape, 2 audio tapes, and several photographs.
Access Terms
Porter, Cole, 1891-1964.; Theatre--United States.
Container List
- an article and note from Jack Aronson, actor (1971);a fountain pen that belonged to George Arliss, stage and film actor (1868-1946) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- correspondence with the Fred Astaire family (Box 1, Folder 2)
- autographs and autographed letters of obscure celebrities, last names A - G (Box 1, Folder 3)
- autographs and autographed letters of obscure celebrities, last names H - M (Box 1, Folder 4)
- autographs and autographed letters of obscure celebrities, last names N - S (Box 1, Folder 5)
- autographs and autographed letters of obscure celebrities, last names T - Z (Box 1, Folder 6)
- correspondence through Dolly Ashley about playwright Edwin Bronner (1972) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- correspondence, columns by Herb Caen, columnist (Box 1, Folder 8)
- information on Communism in the entertainnment industry, including letters, clippings, and concert programs (Box 1, Folder 9)
- correspondence with Mike Connolly, columnist (1959-64) (Box 1, Folder 10)
- correspondence, memorabilia, clippings about George Cukor, film director (Box 1, Folder 11)
- 2 copies, Doc's Apothecary Illustrated Miscellany, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- memorabilia, documents from the estate of Marie Dressler, stage and screen actress (Box 1, Folder 13)
- correspondence with columnist E.V. Durling of the Los Angeles Examiner, 1949-54 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- correspondence with Douglas Fairbanks, Jr. about theater history research, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- correspondence with Morgan Farley, stage and film actor (Box 1, Folder 16)
- correspondence with stage and film actor Jose Ferrer, 1958-59 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- film history, clippings and articles (Box 2, Folder 2)
- correspondence with Henry Fink, scriptwriter and hotel owner, 1958-60 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- correspondence with Billy Hoffman, collector, 1959-60 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- correspondence with and about K. T. Keller, president of Chrysler Corporation, 1946-51 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- clippings, photo of Harry Lewis, actor and restauranteur (founded Hamburger Hamlet) (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Llanuza comic strips from 1912 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- correspondence with Edna May Oliver (Box 2, Folder 8)
- clippings, Cole Porter (Box 2, Folder 9)
- theatre and film souvenir programs (Box 2, Folder 10)
- correspondence with May Robson (1939-42)and a tie she made and gave to Sam Stark in 1938 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- correspondence with writer Alice B. Saarinen (married to architect Eero Saarinen) concerning theatre history (Box 2, Folder 12)
- correspondence about the San Francisco Theatre Union (Box 2, Folder 13)
- correspondence with Arthur Schlobohm, collector, about acquiring a china Floradora Sextet figurine manufactured in 1900 (1973-77) (Box 2, Folder 14)
- correspondence with Eddie Schwartz, advertiser (Box 2, Folder 15)
- issues of the Eddie Schwartz newsletter (Box 2, Folder 16)
- clippings about Gloria Swanson, silent screen and early sound film actress (Box 2, Folder 17)
- correspondence with Victor Allen, screenwriter, actor, and author of Johnny Belinda (Box 2, Folder 18)
- correspondence with Bert(ram) Yarborough, actor and stage director (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Theatre Design - photos, articles, etc. (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Theatre Design - Old European theatres - photos, drawings, etc. (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Theatre History - Baltimore, MD - the Mechanic Theatre (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Theatre History - Venetian marionettes - photos (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Theatre History - minstrels - unidentified photos (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Theatre History - Old American theatres - photos, clippings (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Theatre History - Old California theatres - photos (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Theatre History - The Play Pictorial magazine, 4 issues, nos. 66, 85, 140, 287 (circa 1909-1920) (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Theatre History - San Francisco, CA - the Pantages (Orpheum) Theatre (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Theatre History - St. Louis, MO - clipping, 1970-72 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Theatre History - South San Francisco Opera House - photos, clippings, articles (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Theatre History - Theatre obituaries (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Theatre History - miscellaneous photos, clippings, etc. (Box 3, Folder 13)
- contains the autograph book of Samuel Stark Gertzen from his schooldays at Wenonah Military Academy (1925)and the autograph book of the Viennese actress Edle von Brenneis (1896) (Box 4)
- contains one VHS videotape of An Evening at the White House in Honor of Cole Porter, 2/19/88;2 reels of 1/4 inch audiotape recordings of the USC Friends of the Library Tribute to Cole Porter, 2/12/67,dubbed 5/18/71;4 Cole Porter postcards; one clipping from the 5/15/82L.A. Times concerning Cole Porter's former home; one framed photograph of Cole Porter autographed to Sam Stark; one photograph of inventor Jean A. Le Roy autographed to Roger Imhof; one letter plus enclosures to Sam Stark from Margaret Cole Richards; one framed U.S. Postal Service Cole Porter stamp set (Box 5)
- contains one purple embossed leather scrapbook containing early 19th century documents in Spanish from colonial Latin America; [one red embossed leather scrapbook of theatre programs and theatre-related newspaper clippings, OS to M0622 (Box 6)
- contains one large photo portfolio (woven grass cover) of 688 McCullough Drive, Brentwood, CA - a posh house Greta Garbo once lived in that Samuel Stark co-owned briefly, OS to M0622 (Box 7)
- contains two scrapbooks of vaudeville theatre memorabilia left to Samuel Stark by Roger Imhof, to M0622 (Box 8)
- 4 books of music and lyrics by Cole Porter: Anything Goes, Can-Can, Kiss Me Kate, Songs by Cole Porter; two folders of Cole Porter Centennial memorabilia (Peru, Indiana 6/9/90), to M0622 (Box 9)
- contains one scrapbook - Roger Imhof's autograph collection (1930), OS (Box 10)
- contains a photograph collection of Mr. Stark's (it had been bound in a red vinyl binder) (Box 11)
- Card drawers of additional `Stark Index' cards, added to M0602. (Box 12)